BuzzFeed news editor Ellen Cushing sit
between a lamp and a bamboo plant at a
wooden table in front of a gray backdrop
I'm an editor for BuzzFeed news here in
San Francisco
I'm also legally blind so in my personal
life and in my professional life I've
spent a lot of time thinking about
accessibility in tech Ellen said some
unis looking out the window
Ellen waits at a Muni stop Ellen talks
to Cameron from inside the Muni I cannot
drive which means I often take public
transportation but I also take rideshare
it's completely changed my life
Ellen sits inside a Muni car typing at
her phone while people board my life was
very very different before
uber and existed Ellen still on Muni now
sits next to a metal railed window and
looks at her phone see very far I really
deaf person I really cut back to shot of
Ellen a wooden table in front of grey
backdrop into things a lot I don't have
the same abilities that most people have
even people who wear glasses and things
like that
Apple gave us access to some of its
visually impaired users and we talked to
them about what their lives are like cut
back to Ellen sitting at the back of me
smiling at her phone as she types away
frankly it's a civil rights issue or 1.3
million visually impaired people in the
United States it's really important that
they be able to use the same products
that the rest of us do close up with
Ellen's hands as she fills out boxes on
a crossword puzzle on her phone cut back
to Ellen on Muni talking to camera ology
can really enrich and change the lives
of people with physical and mental
disabilities
there are three blue chairs placed in a
room looking over Civic Center in San
Francisco Tiffany Taylor is sitting in
the middle chair I am primarily a
accessibility consultant and I'm really
passionate about making arts more
accessible adding an audio description
sign language touch tours and those
types of things Tiffany now sitting on
an ottoman in front of a TV
she's holding an Apple TV remote turn on
voiceover boys hidden figures playing we
see the back of Tiffany's head with the
TV in front of her she watches the movie
she looks at him startled he hands her a
fresh piece of chalk holding out his
hand loosely her hand takes the chalk
and she pushes away from the table cut
back to shot of Tiffany sitting on the
Ottoman who she talks to camera so
that's just a sample of the audio
description this scene is pretty visual
and so it really gives a lot of feedback
about the expressions and sort of the
visual nonverbal kind of communication
that's going on not just describing
action but it's also describing
expression and sort of the tone of the
scene that you wouldn't get otherwise
there are some mixed views on that but I
think it's very helpful haben Girma is
wearing a red dress with a Braille
keyboard resting on her lap as she sits
across from BuzzFeed news video producer
Alison lucky and who has a little table
with a QWERTY keyboard placed in front
of her and I'm trained as an attorney
I'm a non-traditional lawyer in that I
focus on teaching companies and
organizations schools nonprofits to see
the value of disability inclusion haben
talks towards Alison's direction behind
her is a view of City Hall in San
Francisco a lot of people have
misconceptions about disability so I
help teach them and help advocate for
greater access for the disability
community Robyn is talking to camera I
have two Braille displays out right now
just so we can do the demo cut back to
shot and I've been smiling intros
Allison types on QWERTY keyboards that's
interesting can you tell me how it feels
good I could also let you feel it
Allisyn types I hope that works too
Robin smiley turns her Braille keyboard
around in Allison's direction allison
inches her way towards the edge of her
seat to get closer to the keyboard cut
to a shot of the Braille keyboard as
Allison types on the QWERTY keyboard cut
to a shot of haben stands as we're right
fingers games across the cursor keys on
the Braille keyboard
so keep right at the top for typing data
we see Hubbins iPhone next to the
Braille keyboard connected by bluetooth
everything on the screen appears in
Braille I'm not negating using voiceover
hand gestures on the phone and whatever
is on the phone shows up in digital
Braille I've been talking to Allison
with haptics I get a buzz when I get a
message as I wouldn't have my phone on
me because I liked wearing Jess's and
don't have pockets but I could still
stay connected and know when someone's
trying to get my attention we see
Hubbins icon next to the Braille
keyboard I think this will encourage
more people to make their apps
accessible and their videos and pictures
accessible we see a video post from
haben since Purim haben and Maxine are
standing in front of a 1911 steam train
captions help deaf individuals access
videos Instagram most of haben on blue
paddle board she's holding a tall paddle
in both hands behind her is a beach with
large sand colored houses and image
descriptions help blind individuals
access pictures Instagram post haben is
reading from a Braille display connected
to her MacBook Air behind her is a
grassy field with soccer nets and trees
so when you post videos add captions on
audio descriptions haben back an
interview were on talking to camera and
on image descriptions for your photos so
everyone could access your story Jordan
caster sitting in the middle of a big
leather couch in the lobby of her
apartment complex on each side of the
couch are two pillows one larger one
designed with leaves and a gray pillow
and resting in front of Jordan I work at
Apple on the accessibility design
qualities Jordan is now outside of her
apartment building standing on the
sidewalk she touches her cane with her
biceps as it rests on her while she
holds up her iPhone and navigates
through it with both hands normal
be the I listened to voiceover so it
looks here like we have an L coming in
seven minutes
and now I'll slow it down
Katie lining inside slash third
Direction imbalances sunnyvale / - or
next departure pelvic Jordan holding
Kane walks toward coming through a
construction walkway when I'm navigating
I'm listening a lot to what's going on
Jordan is now walking the halls of the
Muni station Jordan walks through the
muna gates a Muni metro train closed
after platform Jordan walks toward the
opening doors and gets in
I had a flip phone there was a screen
reader that was on the phone a little
bit it didn't read all the menus it
might only read two levels in or it
might just read my text messages and so
I really didn't have access to the full
capabilities of the phone that I had cut
back to Jordan at leather couch in her
Lobby I also had you know a separate
device for taking notes many documents
many of my books were in hardcopy
Braille Jordan is standing up against
the wall of a Muni train the Muni stops
undid stores openness Jordan exits now I
could have my books my text books on the
iPhone and carry a Braille display close
up at Jordan's face hurricane is in the
shot end in the background we see people
walking the courtyard Y square is really
awesome because it allows me to build
the mental map of San Francisco Jordan
walked down Market Street in San
Francisco Jordan and I'll have a busy
crosswalk the crosswalk changes in
Jordan crosses she is surrounded by a
ton of people crossing the street
first looking bank
Jordan at Blue Bottle coffee is talking
to the cashier a man next to her is
standing making coffee drinks behind the
cashier there are coffee bags stacked on
shelves a woman is making drinks behind
cash you iced mochas ways yes Jordan
holds up her iPhone the screen curtain
turned on
she made it down to the square reader
the square meter flashes four green
lights Jordan called her phone off the
reader and the transaction is complete
Jordan sits at a table outdoors in the
middle of the courtyard behind her is a
fire pit where people are sitting
sometimes people even say excuse me
excuse me ma'am ma'am you're using your
phone and it's it's not turned on and
that's really funny because my phone is
on the screen is just is just turned off
Jordan holds up her phone as she walks
us through accessibility and that's so
if I triple tap my phone with three
fingers people cannot see my phone I can
so use it but the screen is completely
blank so it gives me an added layer of
privacy one of the apps I also really
enjoy using on my phone is called money
reader and this will identify bills just
by holding them in front of the camera
Jordan holds a five dollar bill up to
her iPhone cameras I know what money I
and so it's just another tool of these
technology tools that I have that allows
me to be more independent and efficient
with everyday tasks cut back to Jordan
at leather couch in her Lobby all this
technology just really opened up many
doors and many opportunities that were
not there cut to a shot of Jordans hands
as she types on the Braille keyboard
feature on her iPhone while it's
wonderful it's amazing to have it's a
supplement to the skills that a blind
person needs to have to live a full and
independent life cut back to BuzzFeed
news editor Ellen Cushing in a wooden
table in front of a gray backdrop now we
still have a really really long way to
go I know in my daily life I get
frustrated all the time by tech and user
interface design that's just not
inclusive definitely go on websites that
are just not built for someone to blow
up the font to 18 points certain apps
being broken for voice-over for a really
long time or the AI that identifies
photos just just not working so we still
have a really really long way to go but
I'm really heartened the companies are
working on this