many Americans have disabilities in fact
it's about twenty percent of our
population so you can expect that out of
every five passengers one may have a
disability the goal of this video is to
help you feel comfortable interacting
with these individuals you'll learn the
right words to use and a few terms you
should avoid you'll also learn some
basic techniques for providing
assistance to older adults people who
are blind and passengers who use
assistive devices as you'll see many
people even some wheelchair users can
use standard vehicles and will
appreciate the help you provide
imagine a wall when a person with a
disability is planning an outing what
comes to that person's mind are all of
the obstacles or bricks in a wall that
limit their every move for example buses
with a lack of seating taxis that will
not stop and subways with limited
accessible stops or all barriers by
incorporating the following four steps
you can break down the wall of exclusion
and create a wall of inclusion first the
W in wall the W stands for watch the
observant of passengers and their
abilities if the person looks like he or
she might need additional assistance
approach the person in a friendly manner
and introduce yourself this is
especially important when picking up
someone who is blind or has low vision
observe the passenger and structure your
approach based on that person specific
needs
the all-important a in the wall is for
ask ask the person how may I assist you
if your passenger uses a wheelchair
walker or rollator do not attempt to
dismantle it and store the device
without first asking the passengers
permission a good approach is to ask the
passenger do you have a preference as to
how I stow your wheelchair or other
assistive device remember that an
assistive device is almost like an
extension of someone's body in addition
to assistive devices it is also
necessary to allow service animals to
travel in your vehicle's service animals
should be allowed to ride with the
passenger on the floor of the backseat
of the car be polite and mindful of the
language you use and never hesitate to
ask the person's preferences
the ask leads you to the first L which
is to listen once you ask a passenger
how you may assist it will give you
specific instructions on how to best
accommodate them pay attention to what
the passenger says and then act on what
they say you can also repeat the
instruction for complete clarity if they
don't need or want assistance take no
for an answer
finally the last L is to learn but the
customer know that you understand their
needs and respond appropriately store
this information and the experience to
build your knowledge for the future if
you follow these four letters you will
break down that wall and create a simple
positive experience and a satisfied
passenger here are a few more detailed
tips to help passengers that might need
assistance passenger with a scooter
smaller scooters can be dismantled and
placed in the trunk the seat is
removable the release lever is under the
seat never lift a scooter seat by the
arms it will flip up the tiller can be
loosened and folded down then the
scooter can be lifted into the trunk
always lift from the base this of course
is appropriate for smaller scooters only
if you need to roll the scooter there is
a freewheel lever that you must release
first ask the passenger if they're able
to put the scooter in neutral to avoid
any damage to the scooter passengers
with large scooters need a wheelchair
accessible vehicle with a ramp or lift
passenger with a manual wheelchair there
are two types of wheelchairs power and
manual wheelchairs power wheelchairs
require vehicles that have a lift or
ramp manual wheelchairs come in two
types folding and non folding folding
wheelchairs are collapsible by removing
the seat cushion and pulling up the seat
by moving a release bar or pulling a
cord this type of wheelchair can be
stowed easily in a vehicle trunk or
behind a seat ask the passenger for
their recommendation regarding the best
way to fold the chair non-folding
wheelchairs can be easily disassembled
for stowage the large rear wheels have a
button in the center of the wheel for
removal push the button in hold and pull
the wheel straight out to replace the
wheel keep the button depressed until
the wheel is in place then release and
give the wheel a tug to make sure it is
securely fastened always lift these
chairs by the frame never by the wheels
armrest or footrest ask the passenger
how to set the brakes
passenger who is blind or low vision
passenger with a service animal a person
with a service animal should always be
allowed in your vehicle properly trained
service animals will be easily guided
into the back seat of the vehicle and
onto the floor of the backseat if it is
raining or there is inclement weather it
is helpful to have a blanket or beach
towel in your trunk when guiding someone
who is blind place yourself next to the
blind passenger and allow them to take
your arm do not grab the passenger just
allow them to lightly grasp your elbow
be sure to be very descriptive as you
guide them into your car familiarizing
blind passengers with their surroundings
is welcome help
lastly it's important to use the proper
language when communicating with people
this means that the word handicap is
outdated the preferred term is a person
with disabilities treating all
passengers with respect and dignity will
benefit your business
you